{"1": {"question": "What movement is the first movement of Schumann's Piano Quintet in?", "correct": "Sonata form", "incorrect": ["Rondo form", "Theme and variations", "Strophic"]}, "2": {"question": "What key is Schumann's Piano Quintet in?", "correct": "Eb major", "incorrect": ["Ab major", "Bb major", "Fb major"]}, "3": {"question": "Schumann had not (with one juvenile exception) composed chamber music until what year?", "correct": "1842", "incorrect": ["1840", "1832", "1845"]}, "4": {"question": "What is an obbligato accompaniment?", "correct": "An elaborate and indispensable accompaniment", "incorrect": ["A simple and essential accompaniment", "The melody played in the accompaniment", "An accompaniment obliged to play an accompanying part"]}, "5": {"question": "Prior to 1840, Schumann had only written music for what instrument?", "correct": "Piano", "incorrect": ["Organ", "Violin", "Voice"]}, "6": {"question": "What is Schumann's Liederjahr?", "correct": "Year of songs", "incorrect": ["Knee-lengths leather breeches", "Setting poetry to classical music", "Lid and jar"]}, "7": {"question": "Where and when did Schumann's Piano Quintet Op. 44 premiere?", "correct": "Concert hall of the Leipzig Gewandhaus in 1843", "incorrect": ["Concert hall of the Leipzig Gewandhaus in 1842", "Concert hall of the Leipzig Kupfersaal in 1843", "Concert hall of the Leipzig Kupfersaal in 1842"]}, "8": {"question": "Why is Schumann's Piano Quintet Op. 44 considered a watershed work?", "correct": "It made the Piano and string quartet format the favoured one for Piano quintets", "incorrect": ["It made the Piano and string quartets the disliked format for Piano quintets", "It made the Piano quintet the favoured format", "Because of the flooding in regional NSW"]}, "9": {"question": "Who played piano on Schumann's Piano Quintet Op. 44 in the premiere show?", "correct": "His wife, Clara Schumann", "incorrect": ["His father, August Schumann", "His mother, Johanna Christine Schnabel", "His son, Felix Schumann"]}, "10": {"question": "What did Schumann compose in addition to the Quintet in 1842?", "correct": "Three string quartets, a Piano quartet and a set of Phantasiest端cke", "incorrect": ["Four string quartets, a Piano quintet and a set of Phantasiest端cke", "Three string quartets, a Piano quartet and a set of Phantasiest端cke", "Three string quartets, two Piano quintets and a set of Phantasiest端cke"]}, "11": {"question": "What did Schumann do in his Liederjahr?", "correct": "Turned his attention almost entirely to writing German songs, or Lieder", "incorrect": ["Reflected on all his life choices", "Turned his attention to writing poetry", "Ate some marmalade"]}, "12": {"question": "What is one feature of Schumann's Quintet that distinguishes it from Classical (e.g. Mozart and Haydn) Sonata form?", "correct": "Tendency towards a continuous texture in which many of the ends of thematic units and cadence points elide with the next thematic unit", "incorrect": ["Tendency to get distracted", "Tendency towards a dense texture in which many of the ends of thematic units end in cadences that have dense voicings", "An extensive use of ornamentation and expressive techniques"]}, "13": {"question": "What key is the first subordinate theme in the exposition of Schumann's Quintet in? ", "correct": "The dominant Bb major", "incorrect": ["The dominant Eb major", "The relative major Bb major", "Eb minor"]}, "14": {"question": "How long is the main theme in Schumann's Quintet?", "correct": "8 bars", "incorrect": ["16 bars", "12 bars", "4 bars"]}, "15": {"question": "Schumann's Piano Quintet Op. 44 was dedicated to _______ and remained a staple in her repertoire throughout her long pianistic career.", "correct": "Clara Schumann", "incorrect": ["Johanna Christine Schnabel", "Joan Samantha Bach", "Maria Schumann"]}, "16": {"question": "Which section is the least predictable part of the First movement of Schumann's Piano Quintet Op. 44?", "correct": "Development", "incorrect": ["Exposition", "Recapitulation", "Coda"]}, "17": {"question": "Which instrument is featured in a soloistic role in the development of the first movement of Schumann's Piano Quintet Op.44?", "correct": "Piano", "incorrect": ["Violin", "Viola", "Cello"]}, "18": {"question": "What is the role of the strings section in the development of the first movement of Schumann's Piano Quintet Op.44?", "correct": "Accompaniment", "incorrect": ["Soloistic", "Melodic", "Chairman"]}, "19": {"question": "Which era is Robert Schumann from?", "correct": "Romantic period", "incorrect": ["Classical period", "Baroque period", "Contemporary period"]}, "20": {"question": "Who loved to write proper names such as Abegg, Asch and Bach in musical notation and then use them as themes in his works?", "correct": "Schumann", "incorrect": ["Schubert", "Handel", "Mendelssohn", "Rorschach"]}}